Movement culture, part of what makes it so effective is that it is simultaneously
drawing from the past of everyone who's done versions of that thing and also
creating something that makes it both specific to the moment and points it in
in another direction and so you know the I think the easiest like within the
realm of fine art things are valorized because of newness this sort of idea of
something being like unique or new or special or creating some sort of
like individuated sublime experience and then within the realm of design
things are valorized based on like there are fact largely at I mean what we
tend to see is is designed in the realm of its ability to sell us things to
effectively market something and I think the less visible aspect of design but
just as or more powerful is its sort of securitization that it's legitimization
of governance right right so for me like fine art is is largely the realm of
the expression of the self and design is largely the realm of the expression of
governance and economics and when you're in a movement you're of course
going to draw on those things but that's not the culture we want that's right we
need a culture that is distinct from these things and that culture has been in
constant production for probably as long as there are human beings but
certainly since the advent of capitalism in the way that in our ability to
document and see it iterates so I mean you participate in movements and you see
versions of things that people were doing in the French Revolution yeah exactly
and so for me as a producer of culture it's about sort of being as aware of
that history as I possibly can so that I can more effectively draw on it and
thus in a way like like this is drawing from May 68 but you don't need to know
May 68 you don't need to know like you know under the paving stones the beach
but then I also think my another thing that is important in my work and in how I
feel about movement culture more broadly is that like I'm also continually
repurposing and reusing images that I've made in the past and also
repurposing and reusing images that other people have made and so like this
police car was a stencil that I made for a kind of goofy project with a friend
almost 20 years ago where we made a compilation CD of like 30 different
cover versions of NWA's fucked the police and so George Floyd happened and I
just had this image of this torched cop car that was completely echoing what
was we were seeing in the news that I just happened with me 20 years early
there so my soldiers reuse it and that's like I don't have a lot of
fidelity to I mean I'm always repurposing things
I'll do book cover design and you know I do a lot of book cover design I'll
design three versions of a cover and you know two of them won't get used and
then one of those I'll end up repurposing a decade later for somebody else
that I'll tweak and change and I'm doing that internally in my own work but I
feel like movements are doing that to the entire history of political
graphics all the time yeah and that's part of what makes it so powerful is
that you're part you're like I take great comfort in the fact that like I'm on
the shoulders of lots of other people who did really amazing work I don't have
to do it all myself and I mean all of that too kind of leaks back to with
your work the power of the political poster itself is a form I mean I'm you
know in studying your work and thinking about you know the idea that you wanted
something you know these were designed to be inexpensive designed to be used
designed to be as you said repurposed right and that kind of is in the moment
that we're in that the image has been such a part of the movement and the
in the the cop car on fire right the burning of precincts and so literally
there are these themes out there that just keep emerging and keep coming back
so you know in your work I think a lot about the political poster as part of
that counter visual space to both design and you know the realm of fine art
right that it's a space where part of what is attractive needed all of this work
and do your work specifically is that the world is papered with this right now
right there's this other kind of discourse that just circulates everywhere all
the time but is is not visible in media or you know political discourse
right so part of what we're trying to do is capture that too so I mean I think
it's also important that when you're making work like this is always there's
always this tension between like giving people what they want and giving
people something that challenges them on some level and so like for me
part of it is about trying to like create imagery that has different layers of
potential meaning depending on who's reading them and that you can like
sort of cycle through these that like someone who's like really into riot porn
could look at this image and be like I love the picture an image of wearing
cockroaches and then they they are attracted to the image but then I think
that if you take a little time with it that the images are hooked but it's not
really what the posters about the posters about like how do we build a world
where we feel safe yes and that we may need to burn some coca-cars to get there
but that's not really what matters yes yeah it's actually kind of a relevant
at the end of the day